Norman Kent Papers
Norman Kent Papers
1920-1971
Kent, Norman, 1903-1972.
13.75 linear ft.
The papers of the American printmaker, watercolorist, and editor of American Artist include correspondence, artwork, writings, and memorabilia.
149100
Biographical History
Artist and art educator Norman Kent (1903-1972) graduated from the Rochester Institute of Technology in 1925. He began his career as a Buffalo-based illustrator before teaching at Hobart and William Smith colleges in Geneva. He later served as the editor of American Artist magazine for more than 25 years. Kent was best known for his woodcuts and watercolor landscapes. [From http://artoncampus.rit.edu/artist/64/]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
Spanning 1920 to 1971, the Norman Kent Papers comprise a Correspondence-subject file, Artwork, Writings, and Memorabilia of the American wood-engraver, illustrator, printmaker, and watercolorist (1903-1972). The collection reflects Kent's personal and professional life as an educator, working artist, author, and editor of American Artist.
Arranged alphabetically, the Correspondence-subject file (Boxes 1-24) constitutes the largest portion of the collection, and contains biographical material, family correspondence, and personal and professional correspondence and related material, much of the latter in connection with American Artist. Throughout his career Norman Kent corresponded with artists (John Taylor Arms, Ralph Avery, Isabel Bishop, Charles E. Burchfield, John DePol, James D. Havens, Roy M. Mason, Coulton Waugh, Edward Winter, Andrew Wyeth); libraries and art collections (Albright-Knox Art Gallery, Archives of American Art, Library of Congress, Metropolitan Museum of Art, National Gallery of Art, Old Town Galleries, Rochester Memorial Art Gallery); educational institutions (Art Students League of New York, Hobart and William Smith Colleges, Pratt Institute, Rochester Institute of Technology, Syracuse University); art organizations (American Institute of Graphic Arts, American Watercolor Society, Prairie Print Makers, Print Club of Rochester); and the editorial staff of American Artist (Arthur Guptill, Janice Lovoos, Henry Pitz, Ernest W. Watson, Frederic Whitaker). The correspondence also records the frequent confusion by others of Norman Kent with artists Rockwell Kent and Norman Rockwell, an example of which may be seen in the A. N. Marquis Company's erratum sheet issued for the 1968 edition of Who's Who in America (Box 14).
Artwork (Box 25) contains inventories and lists of Kent's work, 16 of his drawings and prints, and six examples of the work of unidentified artists. The inventories and lists pertain to works that Kent loaned for exhibition, those consigned for sale at a commercial gallery, and collections in which he is represented.
Writings (Box 25) features drafts and published essays as well as book review manuscripts. Most of the writings appeared in American Artist or other periodicals, and exhibition catalogs. Also included in this section are a journal which Kent kept on a 1963 trip to Scandinavia and an undated notebook with drafts of miscellaneous writings.
Memorabilia (Boxes 25-28) includes calendars, financial material, photographs, and printed material. Diary and appointment calendars (1920-1970) document, with only a few short gaps, Kent's student days through his first year of retirement. Financial material (1926-1970) records Kent's art sales, personal finances, and royalty statements. Printed material consists of clippings about Kent or those which were of interest to him. Also included are exhibition announcements and catalogs of Kent's one-man and group shows as well as those of other artists.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Illustrators; Art -- Painters; Arms, John Taylor, 1887-1953.; Avery, Ralph.; Bishop, Isabel, 1902-1988.; Burchfield, Charles, 1893-1967.; DePol, John, 1913-2004.; Guptill, Arthur Leighton, 1891-1956.; Havens, James Dexter, 1900-1960.; Kent, Norman, 1903-1972.; Kent, Rockwell, 1882-1971.; Lovoos, Janice.; Mason, Roy M., 1886-1972.; Pitz, Henry C. (Henry Clarence), 1895-1976.; Rockwell, Norman, 1894-1978.; Watson, Ernest William, 1884-1969.; Waugh, Coulton, 1896-1973.; Whitaker, Frederic.; Winter, Edward.; Wyeth, Andrew, 1917-2009.; Albright-Knox Art Gallery.; American Institute of Graphic Arts.; American Watercolor Society.; Archives of American Art.; Art Students League (New York, N.Y.); Hobart and William Smith Colleges.; Library of Congress.; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); National Gallery of Art (U.S.); Old Town Galleries.; Prairie Print Makers.; Pratt Institute.; Print Club of Rochester.; Rochester Institute of Technology.; Syracuse University.; University of Rochester. -- Memorial Art Gallery.; American artist.; Art -- Societies, etc.; Art, American -- 20th century.; Art publishing -- United States.; Artists -- United States.; Block printing -- United States -- 20th century.; Graphic arts -- United States.; Illustrators -- United States.; Painting, American -- 20th century.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Printmakers, United States.; Sculpture, American -- 20th century.; Watercolor painting, American -- 20th century.; Watercolorists -- United States.; Wood-engraving -- United States -- 20th century.; Account books.; Bankbooks.; Calendars (documents); Clippings (information artifacts); Contracts.; Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Drawings (visual works); Exhibition catalogs.; Inventories.; Manuscripts for publication.; Minutes (administrative records); Notebooks.; Photographs.; Reviews (documents); Woodcuts (prints); Artists.; Editors.; Printmakers.; Watercolorists.; Wood-engravers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Norman Kent, 1965-1975.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject file
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - Family correspondence
    - Kent, Carl H., Jr. (brother), 1955 (Box 1)
    - Kent, Carl H., Sr. (father), 1933 (Box 1)
    - Kent, Suzanne (daughter), 1948-1971; undated (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous relatives (Box 1)
  - A, 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Abbe, Elfriede Martha, 1956-1960 (Box 1)
  - Abeles, Sigmund, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Abell, Walter, 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Harry N. Abrams, Inc., 1955-1964; undated (Box 1)
  - Addison Gallery of American Art, 1957-1967 (Box 1)
  - Ades, Harold, 1966-1970 (Box 1)
  - Adler, Elmer, 1929-1959 (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Charles A., 1964-1969 (Box 1)
  - Albany Institute of History and Art, 1944-1966; undated (Box 1)
  - Albright-Knox Art Gallery, 1930-1964; See also Hekking, William M. (Box 1)
  - Allied Publications, Inc., 1960-1966 (Box 1)
  - Altman, Harold, 1958-1967 (Box 1)
  - The Amateur Artist, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - American Academy of Art, 1960-1961 (Box 1)
  - American Artist
    - Financial, 1955-1960 (Box 2)
    - Form letters (Box 2)
    - Mailing list (Box 2)
    - Office memoranda, 1947-1970; undated (Box 2)
    - Press releases, 1948-1959 (Box 2)
    - Readers' comments, excerpts (Box 2)
    - Resumes (Box 2)
    - Staff meetings, 1955-1959; undated; minutes (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous, 1952-1971; undated (Box 2)
  - American Artists Group, Inc., 1941-1964 (Box 2)
  - American College Society of Print Collectors, See Reitzel, Marques E.
  - American Institute of Graphic Arts, 1933-1956 (Box 2)
  - American National Committee of Engraving, 1940-1941 (Box 2)
  - American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers, See Baer, Carlyle S.
  - American Society of Wood Engravers, 1947-1948; undated (Box 2)
  - American Watercolor Society, 1939-1966; undated (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Ernfred, 1936-1961 (Box 2)
  - Angelo, Valenti, 1935-1969; undated (Box 2)
  - Archives of American Art, 1956-1965 (Box 2)
  - Arellanes, Audrey, 1963-1969 (Box 2)
  - Arms, John Taylor and Dorothy, 1932-1953; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Aronson, Irene, 1959-1968 (Box 2)
  - Art Academy of Cincinnati, See Barnett, Herbert P.
  - Art Association of Indianapolis, Indiana, 1956-1966 (Box 2)
  - The Art Digest, 1943-1951 (Box 2)
  - Art Directors Club (New York, N.Y.), 1953-1962 (Box 2)
  - Art News, 1956-1965 (Box 2)
  - Art Students League (New York, N.Y.), 1935-1967 (Box 2)
  - Arthur, Revington, 1957-1960 (Box 2)
  - Artist Publishing Company, 1956-1959 (Box 2)
  - Artists and Writers Guild, Inc., 1952-1957 (Box 2)
  - Artists' Fellowship, Inc., 1954-1971 (Box 2)
  - Ascher, Mary, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Ashton, Sherley, 1958 (Box 2)
  - Audubon Artists, Inc., 1946-1966; undated (Box 3)
  - Avakian, Lindy, 1959-1960 (Box 3)
  - Avery, Ralph, 1927-1968; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Aylward, W. J., 1947-1948 (Box 3)
  - B, 11 folders (Box 3)
  - Baer, Carlyle S., 1944-1949 (Box 3)
  - Bailey, Merrill A., 1941-1958; undated (Box 3)
  - Bailey, Vernon Howe, 1946-1947 (Box 4)
  - Balcom, Sophia T. (Mrs. Lowell L.), 1939 (Box 4)
  - Baldinger, Wallace S., 1933 (Box 4)
  - Baldwin-Wallace College, 1962-1963 (Box 4)
  - Ballantine, William, 1953-1958; undated (Box 4)
  - Ballinger, Harry R., 1967 (Box 4)
  - Barber, John, 1958-1966 (Box 4)
  - Barnett, Herbert P., 1959-1968 (Box 4)
  - Bartlett, Paul, 1955; 1966 (Box 4)
  - Bassett, Helen Wheeler, 1930-1931; undated (Box 4)
  - Bassford, Wallace, 1963; 1969 (Box 4)
  - Batchelor, C. D., undated (Box 4)
  - Bauernschmidt, Patric, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Baumann, Gustave, 1939-1940 (Box 4)
  - Beaumont, Arthur, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Beckett, Sheliah, 1967-1970; undated (Box 4)
  - Beeler, Joe, 1969 (Box 4)
  - Bell, Enid, 1963-1966; undated (Box 4)
  - Ben Franklin Press, Inc., 1957-1961; undated (Box 4)
  - Beneduce, Antimo, 1961 (Box 4)
  - Bennett, Paul A., 1942-1946; 1963 (Box 4)
  - Benton, Bruce, 1960-1962 (Box 4)
  - Benton, Suzanne, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Berger, Oscar, 1959-1967 (Box 4)
  - Bergstrom Art Center, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Bethlehem Art Gallery, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Betts, Edward H., 1958-1964 (Box 4)
  - Biddle, George, 1940-1943 (Box 4)
  - Biggs, Walter, 1959-1967; undated (Box 4)
  - Billboard Publications, Inc., See American Artist
  - Bishop, Alison, 1940; undated (Box 4)
  - Bishop, Isabel, 1960-1968; undated (Box 4)
  - Blair, Robert N., 1966-1967; undated (Box 4)
  - Blazey, Lawrence, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Bloch, Julia, 1940-1941; undated (Box 4)
  - Blower, David, 1956-1970 (Box 4)
  - Bocour, Leonard, 1964-1965 (Box 4)
  - Bohrod, Aaron, 1958 (Box 4)
  - Bonham, Roger D., 1956-1969 (Box 4)
  - Bookbinder, Jack, 1960-1964 (Box 4)
  - Boston Public Library, 1947-1968 (Box 4)
  - Bouche, Louis, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Boyd, Fiske, 1943-1948 (Box 4)
  - Bradshaw, Glenn R., 1964-1970 (Box 4)
  - Bragdon, Claude, 1935-1946 (Box 4)
  - Brandt, Heidi, 1963-1969; undated (Box 4)
  - Brandt, Rex, 1955-1969 (Box 4)
  - Brangwyn, Frank, 1944-1957 (Box 4)
  - Bransom, Paul, 1948-1960 (Box 4)
  - Breverman, Harvey, 1963-1965 (Box 4)
  - Broemel, Carl W., 1956-1966; undated (Box 4)
  - Brooklyn Museum, 1932-1968 (Box 4)
  - Brown, Arthur William, 1961; undated (Box 4)
  - Browning, Colleen, 1956; undated (Box 4)
  - Bruner, Louise, 1955-1969 (Box 4)
  - Buller, Cecil, 1940 (Box 4)
  - Burbank, Addison, 1941-1942 (Box 5)
  - Burchfield, Charles E., 1929-1967; undated (Box 5)
  - Butler Institute of American Art, 1957-1968 (Box 5)
  - Bye, Ranulph, 1956-1966 (Box 5)
  - Byrnes, Gene, 1943 (Box 5)
  - C, 10 folders (Box 5)
  - Caddell, Foster, 1962-1971; undated (Box 5)
  - Calamar, Gloria, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
  - Calapai, Letterio, 1958 (Box 5)
  - Cameron, Malcolm, 1968 (Box 5)
  - Cameron, William Ross, 1940; 1961-1970,; undated (Box 5)
  - Campbell, H. E. Ogden, 1955-1957 (Box 5)
  - Campbell, Heyworth, 1927-1929 (Box 5)
  - Canaday, John, 1959; 1968,; undated (Box 5)
  - Candell, Victor, 1940 (Box 5)
  - Capps, Charles M., See Prairie Print Makers
  - Carnegie Institute, 1941-1967 (Box 6)
  - Carrington, Fitz Roy, 1931-1935 (Box 6)
  - Carter, Clarence H., 1946-1963 (Box 6)
  - Cassel-Wronker, Lili, 1957-1958; undated (Box 6)
  - Cevasco, George A., 1958-1959 (Box 6)
  - Chamberlain, Samuel, 1942; 1967-1968,; undated (Box 6)
  - Chapin, Barbara, 1943-1960 (Box 6)
  - Chapman, Frederick T., 1940-1971; undated (Box 6)
  - Chapman, Howard Eugene, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Chappell, Warren, 1935-1964; undated (Box 6)
  - Cheffetz, Asa, 1947-1950 (Box 6)
  - Christ-Janer, Albert William, 1965-1968 (Box 6)
  - Clark, Helen, 1956-1964 (Box 6)
  - Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute, 1960-1962 (Box 6)
  - Cleland, T. M., 1942-1947; undated (Box 6)
  - Cleveland Institute of Art, 1949-1961; 1970 (Box 6)
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, 1927-1964 (Box 6)
  - Close, Marjorie, 1969; See also Society of Western Artists (Box 6)
  - Clymer, John, 1954 (Box 6)
  - Cobb, Ruth, 1960 (Box 6)
  - Cober, Alan E., 1966 (Box 6)
  - Coes, Kent Day, 1956-1963; See also American Watercolor Society (Box 6)
  - Cohen, George M., 1958-1966 (Box 6)
  - Cole, Alphaeus P., undated (Box 6)
  - Coleman, John, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Colgrove, Ronald, 1964 (Box 6)
  - Comfort, Barbara, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Connecticut Academy of Fine Arts, 1955-1961 (Box 6)
  - Conrad, Barnaby, 1962-1966; undated (Box 6)
  - Conrad, Rupert, 1961; undated (Box 6)
  - Cook, Howard, 1940-1948 (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Fred, 1940; undated (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Mario, 1955-1968; See also American Watercolor Society; Audubon Artists, Inc. (Box 6)
  - Cornwell, Dean, 1953-1960; undated (Box 6)
  - Costigan, John E., 1947-1968 (Box 6)
  - Cowles, Russell, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Cresson, Margaret French, 1956-1957; 1969 (Box 6)
  - Crilley, Joseph J., 1960 (Box 6)
  - Crimi, Alfred D., 1947-1962 (Box 6)
  - Croughton, Amy H., 1940-1949 (Box 6)
  - Csoka, Stephen, 1957; undated (Box 6)
  - Cunningham, Phelps, 1939 (Box 6)
  - D, 4 folders (Box 6)
  - Dali, Salvador, ca.1956 (Box 7)
  - Daugherty, James, 1939-1968; undated (Box 7)
  - Davis, Fitzroy, 1958 (Box 7)
  - DeGarthe, William E., 1960 (Box 7)
  - Deines, E. Hubert, 1947-1956 (Box 7)
  - Delano, Gerard Curtis, 1960 (Box 7)
  - DeLue, Donald, 1956-1965 (Box 7)
  - DePol, John H., 1947-1956; 1968,; undated (Box 7)
  - Diederich, Hunt, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Dmitri, Ivan, 1959; 1963 (Box 7)
  - Dobrin, Arnold, 1960-1966 (Box 7)
  - Dodd, Lamar, 1956-1968 (Box 7)
  - Dohanos, Stevan, 1965-1967; undated (Box 7)
  - Domjan, Joseph, 1958-1969; undated (Box 7)
  - Donald, Douglas, 1930; undated (Box 7)
  - Dulac, Margarita W., ca.1966 (Box 7)
  - Dunn, Calvin, 1956; undated (Box 7)
  - Dwiggins, W. A., 1937-1945 (Box 7)
  - E, 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Eager, Fred, 1958-1964; undated (Box 7)
  - Edgerly, Beatrice, 1956-1959; 1966 (Box 7)
  - Edmonds, Walter D., 1933-1966 (Box 7)
  - Ehrich, William, 1945-1946 (Box 7)
  - Eichenberg, Fritz, 1944-1968; See also American Institute of Graphic Arts (Box 7)
  - Eisenstat, Benjamin, 1965 (Box 7)
  - Ellis, Dean, 1963 (Box 7)
  - Enabnit, Merlin, 1956-1966 (Box 7)
  - Ennis, David, 1955-1966 (Box 7)
  - Erlanger, Elizabeth N., 1956 (Box 7)
  - Eskridge, Robert Lee, 1956-1957; undated (Box 7)
  - Ettenberg, Eugene M., 1946-1970; undated (Box 7)
  - Evans, Henry, 1969-1970; 1959 (Box 7)
  - Evans, Richard, 1962-1963; undated (Box 7)
  - Everson Museum of Art, 1931-1964 (Box 7)
  - F, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - Fabri, Ralph, 1949-1971 (Box 8)
  - Falls, Charles Buckles and Bedelia, 1938-1962 (Box 8)
  - Famous Artists School, 1956-1966 (Box 8)
  - Farnsworth School of Art, 1956-1969; undated (Box 8)
  - Fawcett, Robert, 1955-1964; undated (Box 8)
  - Federal Art Project, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Finck, Furman J., 1956-1964 (Box 8)
  - Finken, James H., 1937-1938 (Box 8)
  - Fisher, Leonard Everett, 1966 (Box 8)
  - Fitzgerald, Edmond James, 1959-1966; undated (Box 8)
  - Floethe, Richard, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Florsheim, Richard A., 1959-1969 (Box 8)
  - Ford Motor Company, 1952-1966 (Box 8)
  - The Forum, 1928-1929; 1935 (Box 8)
  - Foster, William S., 1962 (Box 8)
  - Fowler, Alfred, 1932-1947 (Box 8)
  - Frasconi, Antonio, 1958-1962 (Box 8)
  - Fraser, Juliette May, 1958 (Box 8)
  - Freund, Rudolf, 1964 (Box 8)
  - Friberg, Arnold, 1958-1961 (Box 8)
  - Fulwider, Edwin, 1961 (Box 8)
  - G, 5 folders (Box 8)
  - Gaertner, Carl, 1947-1948 (Box 9)
  - Gag, Wanda, 1939 (Box 9)
  - Gallery Press, See Ettenberg, Eugene M.
  - Galli, Stanley W., 1952-1956; undated (Box 9)
  - Gasser, Henry M., 1961-1970 (Box 9)
  - Gearhart, Frances H., 1939 (Box 9)
  - Geary, Fred, 1940-1941 (Box 9)
  - Geiszel, John H., 1956; 1965 (Box 9)
  - Geritz, Franz, 1939 (Box 9)
  - Gillen, Denver L., 1956 (Box 9)
  - Gladstone, Myron J., 1955-1959 (Box 9)
  - Glanzman, Louis S., 1963 (Box 9)
  - Glickman, Maurice, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Glitenkamp, H., 1939 (Box 9)
  - Goethe, Joseph, 1959 (Box 9)
  - Goff, Sudduth, undated (Box 9)
  - Gold, Albert, 1956-1961 (Box 9)
  - Gonzalez, Xavier, 1955-1968; undated (Box 9)
  - Goodman, Bertram, 1961-1969 (Box 9)
  - Gordon, Stanley J., 1962; undated (Box 9)
  - Gorman, William D., 1961-1965 (Box 9)
  - Grabach, John R., 1961 (Box 9)
  - Gramatky, Hardie, 1955-1968 (Box 9)
  - Grand Central Art Galleries, 1932-1965 (Box 9)
  - Grand Central Moderns, 1956 (Box 9)
  - Grandee, Joe Ruiz, 1965; 1967 (Box 9)
  - Grant, Gordon, 1945-1956 (Box 9)
  - Grashow, James, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Gray, Gladys, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Greenough, Charles P. and Margaret S., 1959-1965 (Box 9)
  - Gross, Earl, 1946-1970; undated (Box 9)
  - Groth, John, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Grove, Edward R., 1969 (Box 9)
  - Guptill, Arthur, 1943-1956 (Box 9)
  - Guptill, Leighton, 1957-1962; undated (Box 9)
  - Gwathmey, Robert, 1941 (Box 9)
  - H, 7 folders (Box 9)
  - Haines, Richard, 1963 (Box 10)
  - Hale, Nathan Cabot, undated (Box 10)
  - Hammell, Elizabeth Lansdell, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Hammer, Victor and Carolyn, 1943-1967; undated (Box 10)
  - Harbeson, John F., 1959-1961; undated (Box 10)
  - Harding, George, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Hardy, Thomas, 1954-1955 (Box 10)
  - Harms, Ernest, 1956-1961 (Box 10)
  - Harned, Fayette F., 1951-1971; undated (Box 10)
  - Harper and Brothers, 1932-1946 (Box 10)
  - Hartgen, Vincent A., 1956; 1967-1968 (Box 10)
  - Havens, James D., 1927-1961; undated; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - Hawley, Carl T., 1935 (Box 10)
  - Heaney, Charles, 1940 (Box 10)
  - Hechenbleikner, Louis, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Heintzelman, Arthur W., See Boston Public Library
  - Heiter, Michael, 1960; undated (Box 10)
  - Heitland, William Emerton, 1944-1961; undated (Box 10)
  - Hekking, William M., 1932-1944; undated (Box 10)
    See also Albright-Knox Art Gallery
  - Helck, Peter, 1944-1971; undated (Box 10)
  - Heliker, John E., 1954-1955 (Box 10)
  - Heller, Helen West, 1952 (Box 10)
  - Hershfield, Leo, 1954; 1968 (Box 10)
  - Hicken, Philip, 1958; undated (Box 10)
  - Higgins, Eugene, 1947 (Box 10)
  - Hiler, Hilaire, 1961 (Box 10)
  - Hobart and William Smith Colleges, 1933-1965; undated (Box 10)
  - Hobbie, Lucille, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Hodgell, Robert, 1960-1966 (Box 10)
  - Hodges, C. Walter, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Hoeflich, Sherman, 1964-1967 (Box 10)
  - Hoftrup, J. Lars, 1943-1954; undated (Box 10)
  - Hogarth, Burne, 1961; undated (Box 10)
  - Hogarth, Paul, 1959-1964 (Box 10)
  - Hogue, Alexandre, 1962 (Box 10)
  - Honore, Paul, 1929; 1947,; undated (Box 10)
  - Hooks, Mitchell, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Hoowij, Jan, 1956; 1963 (Box 10)
  - Hord, Donal, 1958-1959 (Box 10)
  - Horter, Earl, undated (Box 10)
  - Horton, Al, See Rochester Institute of Technology
  - Hovey, J. Allan, 1961-1967; undated (Box 10)
  - Hungerford, Edward, 1935-1946; undated (Box 11)
  - Hunter, E. Robert, See Norton Gallery and School of Art
  - Hunter, Robert Douglas, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Hunter, Sam, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Huntley, Victoria Hutson, 1959-1961 (Box 11)
  - Hurwitz, Sidney, 1966-1968; undated (Box 11)
  - Hutchinson, Bruce, 1944-1952 (Box 11)
  - I, 1 folder (Box 11)
  - Indiviglia, Salvatore Joseph, 1957; 1962 (Box 11)
  - J, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Jackson, Billy M., 1969 (Box 11)
  - Jamison, Philip, 1961; 1969,; undated (Box 11)
  - Javits, Jacob K., 1957 (Box 11)
  - Jellico, John, 1957-1969; undated (Box 11)
  - Jennewein, Carl Paul, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Jewell, Edward Alden, 1946-1947 (Box 11)
  - Jones, Amy, 1955; 1958 (Box 11)
  - Jones, H. Wendy, 1962 (Box 11)
  - Jones, Lois M., 1958 (Box 11)
  - Jung, Theodor, 1956-1961 (Box 11)
  - K, 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Kane, Margaret B., 1970 (Box 11)
  - Kappel, Philip, 1945; 1947,; 1965-1967,; undated (Box 11)
  - Karsh, Yousuf, 1965; photocopy (Box 11)
  - Keester, George B., 1961-1967; undated (Box 11)
  - Keller, Deane, 1968 (Box 11)
  - Keller, Henry G., 1944-1945 (Box 11)
  - Kelly, Wallace M., 1965-1969 (Box 11)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 1930-1946; 1965,; undated (Box 11)
  - Kester, Lenard, 1955-1969 (Box 11)
  - Kingman, Dong, 1955-1968 (Box 12)
  - Kinney, Troy, 1932-1933 (Box 12)
  - Kinstler, Everett Raymond, 1969-1971; undated (Box 12)
  - Kitteridge, William A., See Lakeside Press
  - Kovner, Saul, 1965-1968 (Box 12)
  - Kredel, Fritz, 1955-1956 (Box 12)
  - Kroll, Leon, 1968 (Box 12)
  - Kuhler, Otto, 1963-1968 (Box 12)
  - Kupferman, Murray, 1968 (Box 12)
  - L, 4 folders (Box 12)
  - Lachman, Harry, 1962-1968 (Box 12)
  - Lakeside Press, 1941-1961 (Box 12)
  - Landacre, Paul, 1947; 1950 (Box 12)
  - Lankes, Julius J., 1931-1933; 1947-1957,; undated (Box 12)
  - Larson, Orville K., 1959 (Box 12)
  - Lathrop, Dorothy P., 1953-1968 (Box 12)
  - Lauck, Anthony, 1957-1961 (Box 12)
  - Laurent, Robert, 1963-1965 (Box 12)
  - Lawrie, Lee, See DeLue, Donald
  - Laynor, Harold A., 1956-1960 (Box 12)
  - Lazzari, Pietro, 1956 (Box 12)
  - Lee, Robert J., 1966; undated (Box 12)
  - Lee, Ruth H., 1937-1938 (Box 12)
  - Leighton, Clare, 1949-1967; undated (Box 12)
  - Leith-Ross, Harry, 1957-1965 (Box 12)
  - Lemos, Pedro Joseph, 1935 (Box 12)
  - Lenski, Lois, 1939 (Box 12)
  - Leven, Boris, 1955-1961 (Box 12)
  - LeViness, W. Thetford, 1962-1966 (Box 12)
  - Levy, Nat, 1961-1963 (Box 12)
  - Lewicki, James, 1962; 1970 (Box 12)
  - Lewis, Allen, 1957-1958; 1939,; undated (Box 12)
  - Lewis, Jeannette Maxfield, 1962 (Box 12)
  - F. Lewis Publishers, Limited, 1955-1967 (Box 12)
  - Libby, William Charles, 1958-1968; undated (Box 13)
  - Library of Congress, 1929-1970 (Box 13)
  - Lindenmuth, Tod, 1939; 1957 (Box 13)
  - Lissim, Simon, 1955; 1958 (Box 13)
  - Lober, Georg J., 1948-1958 (Box 13)
  - Locke, Charles, 1947; undated (Box 13)
  - Lockhart, James L., 1957-1959 (Box 13)
  - Logan, Herschel C., 1939-1948; 1957-1967 (Box 13)
  - Loggie, Helen A., 1968-1969 (Box 13)
  - Longyear, William, See Pratt Institute
  - Lougheed, Robert E., 1954-1958; undated (Box 13)
  - Lovell, Tom, 1955-1963; undated (Box 13)
  - Lovoos, Janice, 1956-1970; undated; 4 folders (Box 13)
  - Low, Joseph, 1959-1963 (Box 13)
  - Luccioni, Luigi, 1968 (Box 13)
  - Luchtemeyer, Edward, 1960 (Box 13)
  - Luitjens, Helen, 1965 (Box 13)
  - M, 7 folders (Box 13, 14)
  - McCracken, Harold, 1958-1969 (Box 14)
  - McCrea, James and Ruth, 1957; 1962 (Box 14)
  - MacDonald, Thoreau, 1942-1966; undated (Box 14)
  - McGill, William A., 1963-1969 (Box 14)
  - McGovern, Robert F., 1956-1965 (Box 14)
  - Mack, Warren B., 1947-1950 (Box 14)
  - McMahon, Franklin, 1956-1963; undated (Box 14)
  - Maldarelli, Oronzio, 1952 (Box 14)
  - Marans, Moissaye, 1960; 1964 (Box 14)
  - Margulies, Joseph, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Marquardt & Company, Inc., 1944-1945 (Box 14)
  - A. N. Marquis Company, 1958-1968; undated (Box 14)
  - Martin, Fletcher, 1947 (Box 14)
  - Martin, Philip L., 1966-1969 (Box 14)
  - Mason, Roy M., 1930-1964; undated; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Matson, Greta, 1956-1957; undated (Box 14)
  - Maurer, Sascha, 1956-1963 (Box 14)
  - Maurice, Ellie, undated (Box 14)
  - Mayer, Ralph, 1961-1970 (Box 14)
  - Mays, Maxwell, 1961; 1962,; undated (Box 14)
  - Mechanics Institute, See Rochester Institute of Technology